[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to tric
Centrist tasa Advanced
Training as you all know I have already
published 58 YouTube videos covering
beginners intermediate and advanced
level Concepts from couple of videos
onwards I've started teaching you the
realtime scenarios where you might
encounter with different types of
obstacles and how can we solve those
obstacles while automating your test
cases by using trient tasa this is our
obstacle 17 in terms of real time
scenarios and this is our lesson 59 in
terms of overall tricentis TSA
training please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video thank
you so in this lesson I'm going to teach
you a real time scenario where you need
to solve an obstacle by using Dynamic
date expression in the scenario we need
to enter tomorrow's date in an edit box
and where we'll be using the methods
like Dynamic date Expressions so let us
go to our obstacles list and see what is
the obstacle that we need to solve for
this is my obstacle which is named as
tomorrow and categorized as easy let us
go for
it so here is the obstacle in order to
complete this obstacle you need to input
tomorrow's date in the text box so this
is your text box you need to enter
tomorrow's days
tomorrow's date so what is
our today's system day so you can see
here at the bottom my system date is
13th October
2024 which means I need to enter
tomorrow's datee which is 14th October
2024 right so it's
dd.mm.yy
[Music]
y format so what I'm going to do here 14
dot 10 do
2024 see as soon as I enter tomorrow's
date your automation problem is solved
okay so how can we achieve this
one let us go to Tri andest
tasa and and as usual we are going to
capture the objects for this particular
obstacle in this folder obstacles folder
right click scan select
application so this is the application
that we would like to scan select the
application and click on scan
for this obstacle we need to capture the
edit box right so go here and this is
my and this is my edit box where I'll be
entering the date tomorrow's datee
select
this and now let us go back to our
obstacle copy the obstacle
name and then name the
module as obstacle name so this is the
only object that we need right now let
us save the
module and close X
scan go to trient tasa you can see here
this is your
obstacle module that we captured so
let's go back to again left side section
which is test case section and this is
where we are creating all the test cases
for each and every obstacle that we are
working from past 16 YouTube videos so
here right click on this obstacles
folder create test case and name the
test case with the same obstacle name
that we copied earlier double click on
this and now to automate our test case
we need to drag the module that we
captured drag and drop onto your test
case so
here to enter tomorrow's date as I told
you as I told you what is our system
date our system date is 13th October
2024 so here what we are going to do we
are going to use the date Expressions
Dynamic date
Expressions open curly
braces enter date so you you can see
here the syntax date and time values can
be calculated by using base
date we can calculate any date by using
base date along with some deviations
that you can display them in user
defined format so you can see here this
is your date function you need to
specify the base date if you have any
base date you can specify sample base
date like this but if I don't specify
any base date is going to take your
system date you can leave this blank and
then you can use offset
offset in our case our offset is + one
day plus one day and then what is your
format my format is dd. mm. y y y y
right that is our obstacle right so here
you need to enter dd.mm.yy y y okay I
can use that format here okay so now
let's go back here now select
this and then what is
our base date our base date is system
date I'm going to leave this as blank
and then specify your offset within
square
brackets what is the offset what is the
offset + 1 D Plus 1 day that is my
offset and again specify the format
within Square braces what is the format
DD do mm do y y y y this is my
format and then close curly braces as
soon as you click somewhere else see now
you this
particular this particular date
expression is correct to validate the
date expression you can right click on
the expression translate the value let
me translate
this see here now now my system date is
13th October and this is displaying 14th
October 20124 in the format that we
require right now let us change the work
state as
complete and now let's save the test
case and let me run this particular test
Quest right click and run in scratchbook
see it entered 14 October 2024 and you
solve this automation problem
successfully so this is how you can
calculate the
date so this is how you can calculate
the date as per your requirement by
using date Expressions Dynamic date
Expressions so if you have any queries
leave your queries in the comment box
I'll try to respond to your
queries hope you all understand the
concept how can we solve an obstacle
where you need to enter tomorrow's date
in an edit Box by using the concepts
called Dynamic date expressions and
calculate tomorrow's datee please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos don't
forget to like and share the video thank
you
[Music]